A Guide to the Arena Stage Collection: Production Photo Books 1960-1999
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
A Guide to the Arena Stage Collection: Production Photo Books 1960-1999
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arena 0019
collection includes 15 boxes comprising 3 cubic feet (4.5 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Arena Stage in the fall of 2006
Biographical Information
Arena Stage was an early leader in the resident theater movement. One of the first not-for-profit theaters in the United States as well as a pioneer of the regional theater movement the Arena Stage was the first regional theater to transfer a production to Broadway, the first invited by the U.S. State Department to tour behind the Iron Curtain and the first to receive a Tony Award. Co-founded in 1950 by Edward Mangum a teacher from the George Washington University, and Zelda Fichandler one of his students, Arena Stage was opened in Washington D.C. to fill the void left by the closing of the National Theater in 1948. Deriving it's name from the idea of "theater in the round," Arena Stage became one of the first resident theaters in the United States, beginning with a company of only eight actors. Today, Arena performs to over 250,000 patrons during a September to June season and employs nearly 200 theater professionals and craft persons, who are responsible for all the costumes and scenery seen on stage. Many now- famous actors took part in Arena Stage productions during the early part of their careers. Some of them include Robert Prosky, Morgan Freeman, Dianne Weist, James Earl Jones, Kevin Kline, Christopher Guest, Yeardly Smith and Samuel L. Jackson. Donated to George Mason University in fall of 2000, the Arena Stage Collection contains materials spanning the theater's 50 year history including production notebooks, photographs, playbills, scrapbooks, scripts and handwritten correspondence and other production materials.
Scope and Content
This series contains bound photo books of select individual Arena Stage productions, including the 1973 production of Inherit the Wind performed in Russian.
Arrangement
By production title
Contents List
- Production Photo Books
  - The Devils 1963-1964 (Box Box 1)
  - Don Juan 1978-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - The Dybbuk 1974-1975 (Box Box 1)
  - Emigres 1979-1980 (Box Box 1)
  - Emigres 1979-1980 (Box Box 1)
  - An Enemy of the People 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - Galileo 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Galileo 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Gemini 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Gemini 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Geniuses 1982-1983 (Box Box 3)
  - God Bless you, Mr. Rosewater 1980-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Hamlet 1977-1978 (Box Box 3)
  - Heartbreak House (Box Box 3)
  - A History of the American Film 1976-1977 (Box Box 3)
  - (Box Box 4)
  - The Imaginary Invalid 1982-1983 (Box Box 4)
  - The Imaginary Invalide 1982-1983 (Box Box 4)
  - Indians 1968-1969 (Box Box 4)
  - Idiots Delight 1978-1979 (Box Box 4)
  - Idiots Delight 1978-1979 (Box Box 5)
  - Julius Caesar 1974-1975 (Box Box 5)
  - Bean 1980-1981 (Box Box 5)
  - K 1981-1982 (Box Box 5)
  - A Lesson from Aloes 1981-1982 (Box Box 5)
  - A Lie of the Mind 1988-1989 (Box Box 5)
  - Long Day's Journey into Night 1975-1976 (Box Box 6)
  - Loose Ends 1978-1979 (Box Box 6)
  - The Lower Depths 1976-1977 (Box Box 6)
  - The Madness of God 1973-1974 (Box Box 6)
  - Major Barbara 1981-1982 (Box Box 7)
  - The Man Who Came to Dinner 1980-1981 (Box Box 7)
  - The Moon in the Yellow River 1961-1962 (Box Box 7)
  - A Midsummer's Nights Dream 1981-1982 (Box Box 7)
  - A Midsummers Nights Dream 1981-1982 (Box Box 7)
  - The National Health 1977-1978 (Box Box 8)
  - Nightclub Cantata 1977-1978 (Box Box 8)
  - Once in a Lifetime 1975-1976 (Box Box 8)
  - Once in a Lifetime 1975-1976 (Box Box 8)
  - One More time 1980-1981 (Box Box 9)
  - On the Razzle (Box Box 9)
  - Pantomime 1980-1981 (Box Box 9)
  - Passion Play 1984-1985 (Box Box 9)
  - The Persecution and Assassination of Jean-Paul Marat 1968-1969 (Box Box 9)
  - The Persecution and Assassination of Jean-Paul Marat 1968-1969 (Box Box 9)
  - Six Character in Search of an Author 1968-1969 (Box Box 10)
  - Screen Play 1982-1983 (Box Box 10)
  - Serjeant Musgrave's Dance 1965-1966 (Box Box 10)
  - Sergeant Musgraves Dance 1965-1966 (Box Box 11)
  - Streamers 1976-1977 (Box Box 11)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire 1977-1978 (Box Box 11)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire 1977-1978 (Box Box 11)
  - Tales from the Vienna Woods 1978-1979 (Box Box 12)
  - Tales From the Vienna Woods 1978-1979 (Box Box 12)
  - The Taming of the Shrew 1963-1964 (Box Box 12)
  - Teibele and her Demon 1979-1980 (Box Box 12)
  - Tin Types 1978-1979 (Box Box 12)
  - Tom 1973-1974 (Box Box 13)
  - Tom Foolery 1981-182 (Box Box 13)
  - The Tot Family (Box Box 13)
  - Two by Samuel Beckett 1973-1974 (Box Box 13)
  - Undiscovered History 1981-1982 (Box Box 14)
  - Undiscovered Country 1981-1982 (Box Box 14)
  - The Wall 1963-1964 (Box Box 14)
  - The Winters Tale 1979-1980 (Box Box 14)
  - The Winters Tale 1979-1980 (Box Box 14)
  - You Can't Take it With You 1979-1980 (Box Box 15)
  - You Can't Take it With You 1979-1980 (Box Box 15)
  - Russian Tour 1973 (Box Box 15)
  - The 1940's Radio Hour 1978-1979 (Box Box 15)